<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: life | Honey Darling]]></title>
  <link href="http://honeyd.github.io/blog/categories/life/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://honeyd.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-12T19:37:48-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://honeyd.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Honey Darling]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Life Without a Smart Phone]]></title>
    <link href="http://honeyd.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/life-without-a-smart-phone/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-25T11:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://honeyd.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/life-without-a-smart-phone</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Anyone who has seen my fingernails will attest to the fact that I am a compulsive person. Having a smart phone in my pocket gets along real well with my compulsive tendencies. I check it every few minutes. I&rsquo;m especially satisfied to feel the vibration or hear the chime that means there is <em>something to look at</em>. I&rsquo;m looking at my phone at inappropriate times: during dinner, while I&rsquo;m with my kids, in a meeting, <em>while I&rsquo;m driving</em>. I try to moderate, putting my phone somewhere inconvenient or turning it off, but I&rsquo;m still constantly checking for it, going and getting it, thinking about it.</p>

<p>My phone just isn&rsquo;t important enough to me, really, to spend so much time with it. There are so many other things I&rsquo;d rather think about!</p>

<p>There are a couple of disadvantages to not having a smart phone that I had to consider.</p>

<ul>
<li>No access to the Internet means I won&rsquo;t be able to quickly look something up when I&rsquo;m out and about.</li>
<li>I won&rsquo;t have a way to easily play music in the car when my daughter says &ldquo;I want kid&rsquo;s songs!&rdquo;</li>
<li>My phone will not be a media player, so no more podcasts.</li>
<li>I won&rsquo;t be able to take decent photos with my phone, which means either no pictures or carrying around a bulky digital camera.</li>
<li>Texting will likely be harder, and receiving photo messages will be small and distorted.</li>
</ul>


<p><img class="right" src="/images/pantech.jpg">
Choosing a phone that is not a smart phone is not very fun. I bought a Motorola Razr on Ebay, but because it was an unlocked phone and not an AT&amp;T phone, picture texts didn&rsquo;t work at all, so I ended up just using an old phone we had laying around. At least it has a keyboard. That helps.</p>

<p>The first couple of weeks without my beautiful smart phone were pretty hard. I kept feeling for it in my pocket and realizing that it just wasn&rsquo;t there. I&rsquo;d pull out my new phone and be immediately disappointed. There&rsquo;s just nothing to do with it! Especially when there is a lag in my daily life, waiting in line somewhere for example, I notice that I want my smart phone, but then I just stand there instead. I notice all the other people standing around looking at their phone. I never noticed them before because I was one of them. I rode by a bus stop the other day, and of the 10 or so people waiting for the bus, 9 of them were looking at their phone. I&rsquo;m one part jealous and one part amazed by the fact that most people are just like me.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m not taking pictures, I&rsquo;m not keeping up with Facebook, I&rsquo;m seeing new emails in the morning when I get to work, I&rsquo;m not constantly connected, I&rsquo;m beginning to feel more comfortable in the in-between times, when I&rsquo;m alone with myself, with nothing to do. Sometimes doing nothing is nice.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
